Finding Aid for Stephen M. Ross School of Business (University of Michigan) records, 1916-2017
Bentley Historical Library
- Architectural Records, 1943-1998
  - Topical Files, 1943-1976; 1998
    - Business Administration Assembly Hall, Revised, September 13, 1975 (Box 112)
    - School Landscaping, 1972-1976 (Box 112)
    - The University of Michigan Campus Plan-Phase 1 Overview, April 22, 1998 (Folder 4)
- Archived Stephen M. Ross School of Business Website, 1996-ongoing
  The Website series documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the Stephen M. Ross College of Business. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the Ross College of Business. The website series is arranged chronologically and includes content captured by the Internet Archive starting in 1996 as well as captures provided by Bentley Library archivists in 2002, 2003, 2006 and 2008. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at https://archive-it.org/organizations/934.
  - Homepage
    - 1996-[ONGOING]
      (These versions were preserved by the Internet Archive and are made available through its Wayback Machine. The Bentley Historical Library is not involved in the collection or maintenance of this material.)
    - May 15, 2002, .ZIP file
    - June 22, 2003, .ZIP file
    - March 13, 2006, .ZIP file
    - May 30, 2008, .ZIP file
    - 2010-2014
    - 2014-[ONGOING]
  - Related websites, 2010-[ONGOING]
- B.Joseph White Files, 1994
  The B. Joseph White series (2 linear feet) contains a limited amount of materials from White's term as dean of the Business School.
  - Administrative Files
    - History of the School of Business Administration materials, 1928-1995 (scattered dates) (Box 113)
  - Programs, 1994
    - Global Leadership Program, 1994; 5 folders (Box 114)
  - Executive Education Center Faculty Materials, 1995-1996
- Development and Alumni Relations Records, 1929-2007
  The Development and Alumni Relations records subgroup (11.2 linear feet, 12 boxes) is organized into three series: Development Office records (1929-2007), William Davidson Institute (1989-2007) and Reunions (2002). Materials include administrative records, committee agenda, minutes, and notes, material on the establishment of educational institutes, and financial information. Parts of this subgroup carry an executive restriction.
  - Development Office Records, 1929-2007
    The Development Office records series (9.4 linear feet), 1929-2007, is arranged into four sub-series: Administrative Files, Campaigns, Committees, and Educational Institutes. Administrative files (1929-2006) includes articles, correspondence, records related to Dean Robert J. Dolan, financial material, strategic planning documents, photographs of the construction of Sam Wyly Hall, and other administrative material. The Campaigns sub-series (1979-2007) documents the various capital campaigns and fundraising activities of the Ross School of Business. Committees (1970-2002) is comprised primarily of meeting material of the Development Advisory Board. The Educational Institutes (1986-2007) documents the establishment and activities of various endowed educational institutes and programs administered by the Ross School of Business. The majority of records in this series carry an executive restriction of twenty years (July 1, 2029) and a small subset are restricted until July 1, 2037.
    - Administrative Files, 1929-2006
      - 75th anniversary material, 1998-2000; 3 folders (Box 124)
      - Annual reports, 1995-2002 (Box 120)
      - Articles and news releases, 1995-2000 (Box 119)
      - Articles on C.K. Prahalad, 2001-2006 (Box 120)
      - Business School class photographs, undated (Box 127)
        (Photo reproductions of classes 1926-1943.)
      - Business School rankings, 1998-2006 (Box 120)
      - Business Enterprise Trust Partnership Proposal, 1998 (Box 121)
      - Competitiveness data, 1998-1999 (Box 117)
      - Correspondence, 1991-1992; 2 folders (Box 124)
      - Correspondence, Herbert F. Taggart, 1929-1983 (Box 124)
        (Taggart, Herbert F.)
      - Dean Robert J. Dolan
        - Dean Robert J. Dolan file, 2001-2004; 2 folders (Box 119)
          [Executive records restricted until July 01, 2024 ]
        - Robert Dolan appointed dean, 2001 (Box 121)
        - Dean search, 2000 (Box 117)
        - Pre-reads, 2000-2001; 2 folders (Box 125)
      - Diversity publication, 2003 (Box 120)
      - Domestic Corps promotional material, 2003-2004 (Box 120)
      - Domestic Corps summer internship video, 2003-2004
      - Donors
        - Topical files, 1986-2005; 13 folders (Box 126)
          [Executive records restricted until July 01, 2025 ]
        - Correspondence, 1990-1994; 7 folders (Box 126)
      - Effect of compassion at work, 2001 (Box 125)
      - Emeritus reunions printed material, 1999-2002 (Box 120)
      - Facility naming opportunities, 1973; 2005-2007; 2 folders (Box 121)
      - Faculty correspondence, 1989-1995 (Box 118)
      - Financial Material
        - Charitable Remainder Trust, 2001-2003 (Box 122)
          [Executive records restricted until July 01, 2023 ]
        - Funding proposals, 1985-1988; 2 folders (Box 124)
        - Growth Fund, 1985-1990; 4 folders (Box 122)
        - Maize and Blue Fund Proposal, 2006 (Box 121)
          [Executive records restricted until July 01, 2026 ]
        - Management review analysis 03-04 budget, 2003-2004 (Box 121)
        - Seed Capital Fund, 1995-1997; 2 folders (Box 122)
      - Itineraries, Dean Whitaker, 1984-1990 (Box 121)
      - Mitsui Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1989-1990; 2 folders (Box 124)
      - Monroe Street Journal, October 11, 2004 (Box 120)
      - Naming guidelines, 2000 (Box 121)
      - Organizational charts, 1968-1984 (Box 118)
      - Paul W. McCracken dinner, 1988 (Box 122)
      - Private support for public higher education, 1980-1983 (Box 118)
      - Program review, 2002 (Box 121)
      - Scholarship dinner, 2002 (Box 125)
      - Strategic planning, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 118)
      - Success IQ article, 2000 (Box 120)
      - Talking with donors in the aftermath of a crisis, 2001 (Box 121)
      - Vision and goals, 1987-2000; 2 folders (Box 125)
      - Wyly Hall construction photographs, 1998; 11 envelopes (Box 127)
      - Wyly Hall contact sheets, 1998 (Box 127)
      - Alumni Clubs, 2001
    - Campaigns, 1979-2007
      - Emeritus scholarship, 2003-2004; undated (Box 117)
      - Building campaign, 1980-1982 (Box 118)
      - Building campaign dedication, 1981-1986; 2 folders (Box 121)
      - Building campaign, Sam Wyly Hall, 1995-2000; 2 folders (Box 122)
      - Campaign planning
        - 1988-1989 (Box 118)
        - 1990-1991 (Box 119)
        - 1992-1993 (Box 119)
        - 1999-2000, 3 folders (Box 119)
        - Financial reports, 1982-1992 (Box 119)
        - Needs, opportunities, trends, 1999-2001 (Box 121)
      - Capital campaign priorities and objectives, 2002 (Box 121)
      - Case statement and early development planning, 1979-1988 (Box 119)
      - Case statement working group, 2000-2003; 3 folders (Box 121)
      - Counting standards, 2003; undated (Box 121)
      - Faculty dinner, 2000 (Box 119)
      - Faculty forum, 1999-2000; 2 folders (Box 119)
      - Library building groundbreaking, 1982 (Box 121)
      - Post-campaign fundraising program, 1996 (Box 118)
      - Prospectus material, 2003 (Box 119)
      - Post-campaign 3-5 year planning, 1998-2002 (Box 119)
      - Report and printed material, 1995-1997 (Box 120)
      - Scholarship opportunities, 2000 (Box 121)
      - Timeline, 2002 (Box 121)
      - Update, March 1993-1994 (Box 119)
      - Volunteer notebook, 1991 (Box 119)
      - Whitaker Professorship
        - Correspondence and notes, 1997-2000; 2 folders (Box 122)
        - Professor Whitaker remembrance, 2007 (Box 122)
          [Executive records restricted until July 01, 2027 ]
    - Committees, 1970-2002
      - Alumni Society Board of Governors
        - Board meeting and reunion conference, September-October 2000 (Box 125)
        - Membership and annual reports, 1970-1985 (Box 125)
      - Board membership lists, 1991-1998 (Box 117)
      - Development Advisory Board
        - Campaign presentation, 1990-1991 (Box 119)
        - Correspondence, 1981-1989 (Box 118)
        - Meetings
          - Meeting material, 1998-1999; 3 folders (Box 118)
          - August-November 1999 (Box 121)
          - Notes and questions, October 13, 1999 (Box 121)
          - Pre-reads, November 1999 (Box 121)
          - Presentations, November 1999 (Box 121)
          - Break-out notes, November 1999 (Box 121)
          - Sample packet, November 1999 (Box 121)
          - April 7, 2000 (Box 121)
          - November 10, 2000 (Box 121)
          - November 2001 (Box 125)
          - Corporate Advisory Board meeting, 2001 (Box 125)
        - Purpose, undated (Box 121)
        - Rosters, 1999-2002 (Box 121)
      - Joint Advisory Board
        - Meeting material, 1999-2001; 2 folders (Box 118)
      - Leadership Transition Task Force, 2000 (Box 118)
      - Recognition Analysis Committee report, 2001 (Box 121)
    - Educational Institutes, 1986-2007
      - Center for Corporate Responsibility and Sustainable Peace, 2001-2002 (Box 124)
      - Center for the Study of Corporate Finance, 1986-1990; 2 folders (Box 124)
      - Environmental Management Institute
        - 1998-1999 (Box 122)
        - Annual report and publications, 2006-2007 (Box 120)
        - Corporate Environmental Management Program (CEMP), 1998-2004; 2 folders (Box 122)
        - Gifts, 2004-2005 (Box 122)
      - Institute for Entrepreneurial Studies, 1993-2007; undated; 21 folders (Box 123)
      - Institute for Global Sustainable Enterprise, 2006-2007; 2 folders (Box 122)
      - Non-profit public management, 2001-2003 (Box 124)
      - Office for the Study of Private Equity Finance, 1999-2002 (Box 124)
      - Office of Tax Policy Research, 1992-2002 (Box 124)
      - Real Estate Development Institute, 2000 (Box 124)
      - Tauber Manufacturing Institute, 2000-2007 (Box 124)
  - William Davidson Institute, 1989-2007
    The William Davidson Institute series (1.8 linear feet), 1989-2007, is primarily comprised of correspondence and Board of Directors material including meeting minutes, agendas, notes, handouts, and presentations. The material in this series has an executive restriction and is closed for twenty years (July 1, 2029).
    - Articles of incorporation and bylaws, 1992-2006 (Box 117)
    - Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 116)
    - Board of Directors meetings
      - 1995-2002, 16 folders (Box 116)
      - 2003-2007, 8 folders (Box 117)
      - Agendas and minutes, 1992-2007; 2 folders (Box 117)
    - Letters of congratulations, Dr. William Patton, 1989; 2 folders (Box 117)
      (On the occasion of his 100th birthday.)
    - Program year review, 1994-1995 (Box 117)
  - Reunions, 2002
    - Reunion 2002: Promotional Campaign Guide, Class of 1982 (Box 142)
- Robert J. Dolan Files, 2003-2012; undated
  The Robert J. Dolan subgroup (1 linear feet) contains records produced during Dolan's term as dean from 2003-2012. Materials include a copy of a strategic facilities plan and digital files containing administrative documents.
  - Strategic Facilities Plan: Project Definition Report, 2005 (Box 140)
  - Testimonials, 2006-2007 (Box 141)
  - FTMBA: Admit Binders, 2007-2008
  - Print Materials, 2003; 2009-2012
  - Branch Launch Ross, undated
  - Ross Finanace Brochure, undated
  - Ross Employment Profile, 2008
  - Statement of Community Values Handout, 2008
  - Alumni Brochure, 2009
  - Paton Scholarship Brochure, 2009
  - Investors Report; Phd Faculty Research Directory, 2009
  - Evening MBA Admit Brochure, 2007
  - Erb Brochure, 2007
  - Commencement Brochure, 2009
  - Recruiters' Guide, 2012
  - Career Tracker, 2006
The Bentley Historical Library has two additional Ross School of Business (University of Michigan) collections: oral history interviews and publications.
Ross School of Business (University of Michigan) oral histories
Ross School of Business (University of Michigan) publications